#### Nouman Ali

Brooklyn, NY 11230 347-977-6041 | Alinouman003@gmail.com

#### **Selenium Quality Assurance Automation Tester**

More than for 4 years of experience in the field of Software Quality Assurance with expertise in Automation and Manual Testing. Experience with Agile Scrum and Waterfall and TDD (Test Driven Development) methodology. Designed and Developed Automation Test Framework using Selenium WebDriver. Good exposure to the Bug Life Cycle and Automation Framework. Expert in Testing Life Cycle including Risk Analysis, Planning process, Test Design, Performance Test, Defect Tracking and Test Reporting. Experience in Database Testing, Functional Testing, Stress Testing, Regression Testing, Smoke Testing, Load Testing and System Testing. Professional experience in designing Test Cases and Test Scripts and Good exposure to Automation Framework. Good experience in Performance testing using Jmeter. Flexible team player who prospers in a fast-paced work environment and always keen to learn new technologies and look for advancement.

#### **Key Skills**

- SQA Testing & Methodologies
- Test Plans, Cases & Processes
- Functional Testing
- Defect/Bug Tracking

- Scripting & Documentation
- Regression & Negative Testing
- UI & Compatibility Testing
- Test Strategies & Coverages
- Test Automation Framework
- Mobile App Testing
- API Testing/ Database testing
- Performance Testing

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Capital One Bank, Queens, NY Selenium Automation Tester

Responsibilities

- Developed test automation framework based on Page Object Model, TestNG and Selenium Web Driver.
- Worked with developers and the testers to verify test cases.
- Performed Functional, Negative, Positive, Integration, Regression, End to End and User Acceptance Testing.
- Analyzed testing results, identify issues and report to the developers and project managed through JIRA.
- Developed and execute Automation Test Scripts using Selenium and Testing framework.
- Setup Selenium WebDriver to run Selenium scripts on different browsers.

**Environment**: Selenium WebDriver, TestNG, Cucumber, Maven, Jenkins, GitHub, Java, Windows, Oracle, MS Office Tools, MS Outlook, SharePoint, JIRA, XML, HP ALM, Eclipse IDE, Agile.

## **Lenox Hill Radiology,** Brooklyn, NY **Quality Assurance Tester**

Responsibilities:

- February 2017 –April 2018
- Extensively involved in the complete STLC and SDLC activity from requirements gathering to UAT testing.
- Involved in functional testing, regression testing, system testing, integration testing, security testing, configuration testing, GUI testing and User Acceptance Testing (UAT).
- Involved in Identification of test cases to automate using Cucumber.
- Involved in Problem solving and Defect Tracking Tools like JIRA.
- Worked in Performance/Load and Stress testing with JMeter.
- Performed Automation testing using UFT.

May 2019 - January 2020

rough IIDA

### **Nouman Ali**

## Brooklyn, NY 11230 347-977-6041 | Alinouman003@gmail.com

# Coney Island Auto Parts, Brooklyn

January 2015 - March 2017

**QA Tester** 

Responsibilities:

- Designed and implemented test plans to verify new software features and bug fixes
- Extensively involved in the complete STLC and SDLC activity from requirements gathering to UAT testing.
- Used SQL queries to test the backend database.
- Reported and documented technical issues.
- Involved in Problem solving and Defect Tracking Tools like JIRA.
- Involved in functional testing, regression testing, system testing, integration testing, security testing.
- Reviewing and analyzing system specifications.

Environment: MS Word, Visual basic, Visio, MS Excel, Test Director, Windows,

#### **EDUCATION**

**BS, Information Technology** 

(Degree Expected- April 2021)

(Concentration: Cybersecurity), Southern New Hampshire University

GPA 3.70